PRESCOTT OFORI NYAMEKYE

Mobile: +233 (0) 55 469 7739| Email: nyamekyeprescott3@gmail.com

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/OforiPrescott">https://github.com/OforiPrescott</a> | LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/prescott-nyamekye">https://www.linkedin.com/in/prescott-nyamekye</a>

**PROFILE** 

myself.

I am young hardworking, serviceable, cheerful and charitable. I have an intense desire to learn more anywhere I find myself. It is my goal to combine my range of experiences with my abilities, passion and enthusiasm to become an intelligent worker who will make a positive contribution anywhere I find

**TECHNICAL SKILLS** 

• Programming Languages: Python, C++, JavaScript

• Database: MySQL, SQLite, Microsoft SQL Server 2019.

• Other language/framework: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap.

• Soft Skills: Report Writing, Communication, Teamwork

• Languages: English (fluent), Akan (fluent)

FEATURED PROJECTS

**Title**: Police Record Management System for Ghana Police Service

Developed a Police Record Management System for Ghana Police Service where the system accept, store, and make available records of all personnel in the Police Service. The system keep detailed account of suspects and convicts. Also, the system make available portal for crime reports from public. The system examines the validity and authenticity of crimes reported online before opening investigations into them. Finally, the system request information from crime reporters to determine their demography.

Title: Global Weather Checker

Developed a Global Weather Checker which was built in HTML, CSS and JavaScript. In using the Global Weather Checker, you can get the weather details of a particular city by entering the city name or you can also get your current location weather details by clicking on the "Get Device Location" button. In using the app you'll get many weather details such as the temperature in degrees Celsius, weather conditions, location, feels like, and humidity.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ghana-India Kofi Annan Centre of Excellence in ICT

Accra, Ghana

Research Study Assistant

National Service November. 2022 - Present

- Responsible for Data collection. Collecting and organizing data relevant to the study, such as survey responses, code repositories, and performance metrics.
- Data analysis. Analyzing the collected data using appropriate methods, such as statistical analysis
  or code review.
- Coding, testing and documenting the software developed as part of the study, as well as testing and debugging existing code.
- Helping the team with other tasks as needed and providing general support to the research team.

Valley View University

Techiman, Ghana

Computer Lab Assistant

Work Study, August. 2020-2022

- Providing Technical support to students and faculty members who are using the computer lab, including trouble shooting hardware and software issues, helping users with software installation and answering technical questions.
- Maintaining and troubleshooting the lab's equipment, such as computers, printers, and other
  peripherals. This includes ensuring that all equipment is in good working order, and making
  repairs as needed.
- Setting up lab equipment and software as per the course equipment
- Managing the IT-related aspects of the lab, such as backing up data, monitoring system, keeping
  detailed records of lab usage, system and network performance, and any other information
  relevant to the lab's operation. Performance, and ensuring compliance with university IT policies.

Kwabre East Municipal Assembly

Mamponteng, Ghana

IT Assistant

Intern, August. 2019.

- Managing and maintaining the municipal assembly's network infrastructure and computer systems, including configuring network and system settings, troubleshooting issues, and ensuring system and network security.
- Ensure that the municipal assembly's IT systems and practices are in compliance with relevant laws and regulations.
- Provide first level support through phone, e-mail or in-person to resolve IT issues.
- Managing and maintaining the municipal assembly's website, including updating content, resolving technical issues, and ensuring the website's security.

## **EDUCATION/ CERTIFICATIONS**

Valley View University Accra, Ghana

Bachelor of Science Information Technology August 2019- August 2022

Boa Amponsem Senior High School Sept. 2015-Sept. 2018.

Supraja Technologies Certification: Online Internship on Ethical Hacking and Cyber Security (CEH-V10)

Ghana Tech Lab Mobile App Development: MIT App Inventor, Kodular and Thunkable.

Data Camp Certification: Introduction to Python, Intermediate Python.

## **LEADERSHIP AND SERVICE**

Vice President Information Student Association Valley View University 2021-2022

President Youth Mappers Valley View University 2020-2021